

## AMZATH ALI MOHAMED ANSARI

Email: Amzath.pulse@gmail.com Mobile No: +971502156390

To seek a position with your esteemed organization that will present challenges and Stimulation, whereby I can render valuable and productive contribution and achieve Personal growth and Industry recognition through dedicated Sales & Marketing and Operation & Sales Manager Service, Sincere and Efficient efforts at work and Achieving better results for the company.

Moreover 5+ years supporting Sales and executive Skills includes, client relations, Strength to negotiate and close the projects on value, On Time invoicing and payment follow up, project management, Approach consultant and Authorities to get an approval for product, Responsible to deliver the material at end user, prepare the documents to clear the customer, Maintain the stock in warehouse and The ability to maintain a cool head under stressful circumstances.

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

OXCOMM – Oxfordshire Communications Limited - UK, Dubai Branch as Sales & Business Development and Project Management for UAE (NOV 2016 to till date)

Innogulf Solutions - DWC (L.L.C), Dubai as Sales and Operation Manager (Nov 2014 to Nov 2016)

Al Masaood Logistic, Abu Dhabi as Asst. Logistic and Operation Manager (2010-2014)

## **SKILLS**







# JOB PROFILE / OXCOMM - OXFORDSHIRE COMMUNICATIONS LTD UK, Dubai Branch.

## Sales & Business Development and Project Management for UAE

**Employment Duration:** Nov 2016 to Present

## **Projects Handled:**

- **♣**Dragon Furniture Showroom Dubai
- **↓**World Island Sweden Villa Dubai
- ♣Arjan Residency Building Dubai
- ♣Ahad Towers Business Bay Dubai
- ♣Adagio Palm Hotel Dubai
- ♣Serafi Mall Jeddah

## **Systems Handled:**

- **♣**Structured Cablina Systems SCS
- **♣**Security System CCTV
- **♣**Access Control ACS
- ♣Fire Alarm & Fire Fighting
- **4**Central Battery
- **♣**Gate Barrier

## JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Find, develop, build and grow client relationships through active sales and marketing efforts
- Build a pipeline and execute on early stages of the sales process
- Focus on revenue growth through setting and meeting aggressive revenue targets
- Excellent communication, relationship-building + presentation skills
- Strong work ethic, personal initiative + ability to work well in team environment
- Achieve quarterly quotas of qualified opportunities and closed business
- Work on Engineering to freeze B.O.Q for each system based the project specification.
- Prepare Technical Submittal for each system for client's approval.
- Raising Material Request for B.O.Q materials for all System & follow up for deliveries.
   Tracking & maintaining the project costing within the limit.
- Generate Project plan for complete systems.
- Coordinating with factory people for techno-commercial activities.
- Initiating site surveys & reviewing the reports.
- Follow-up on approvals on Material Submittal, Mock up installation, Drawings, Technical Submittal, etc.
- Generate delivery log, invoicing & collection schedule, installation & commissioning schedule. Invoicing based on the project contract.
- Tracking and maintaining delivery, installation & commissioning activities with planned schedule.

- Allocating manpower resources at site considering the allowed costing for the specific activity.
- Providing on site assistance for any technical issues for SCS & CCTV.
- Track project status and report on a regular basis.
- Manage projects to time, budget and customer satisfaction.
- To support the Commissioning activities to achieve the Sequence of Operation specified by client.

#### JOB PROFILE / INNOGULF SOLUTIONS - DWC

## Sales and Operations Manager – ELV Systems

**Employment Duration:** Nov 2014 to Oct 2016

## **Projects Handled:**

- ♣Sheika Fathima Villa, Abu Dhabi
- **♣**Sheik Zayed Majlis, Abu Dhabi
- ♣Security and accommodation villas Sea Palace, Abu Dhabi
- ♣Admin Building AL Bahar Palace, Abu Dhabi
- ♣Main Majlis Sheik Mohamed Bin Zayed, Abu Dhabi.

## JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Drive sales growth by finding and engaging qualified prospects via phone and email
- Directs development of new sales with existing Business Partners
- Estimation verification from project documents.
- Experience in design, implementation and testing in Structured Cabling System
- Strong analysis experience focusing on CCTV system designing, planning and installation.
- Processing purchase orders and related documentation
- Coordinate freight and delivery
- Support installation team to follow manufacturer guidelines and industry best practices
- Coordinate with consultants and client representatives for approvals

# JOB PROFILE / AL MASAOOD LOGISTIC

# AlMasaood Logistics, Abu Dhabi Assistant Operations and Logistics Manager

Employment Duration: Jul 2010 to Sep 2014

# JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Management of import and export shipments
- Issuance of proforma Invoices to customers for establishing export LCs L/C management and fully conversant with the import /export procedures.

- Responsible for customs & shipping documents and arranging delivery of shipments as
  per the delivery / inco terms (CFR, CIF, FOB, EX WORKS etc.) with regards to all inbound
  and outbound shipments.
- Coordination with logistic companies and shipping lines to organize the import and export shipments.
- Coordination with other departments in operation and documentation proceedings to attain a smoth company transection. Motivating others members of the team
- Tracking and maintaining delivery, installation & commissioning activities with planned schedule.
- Initiate change control to ensure that management is aware of all possible changes in project scope.
- Manage projects to time, budget and customer satisfaction.
- To support the Commissioning activities to achieve the Sequence of Operation specified by client.
- Complete project handover to clients/service.
- Ensure project closeout with customer satisfaction.
- Coordinating with manufacturers & suppliers in techno-commercial activities.

#### **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION**

Course of Study
Bsc Electronic Science (Completed 2 years study)

Branch
Industrial Electronics

> University
Bharathidasan University, Tamil Nadu, India

Additional Course
IATA/UFTAA Foundation & EBT – Montreal – Canada

#### **PERSONAL DATA**

Name : Amzath Ali Mohamed Ansari

Age : 33 Years Old

Sex : MaleNationality : Indian

Date of BirthMarriage StatusMarried

> Religion : Muslim

Visa Status
 On Residence Visa Until AUG 2020

## **REFERENCES**

1. Mr. Mohammed Asif (Al Ghurair ELV Divisions) - Manager – ELV Divisions Contact: +971 54 300 0427

Email: mohideen@agcew.ae | wedsite: www.agcew.ae | AL Barsha Dubai - UAE.

2. Mr. Tj Q`reshi (OXCOMM - UK) - Director – Global Marketing Contact +44 7782 217000

Tel: +44 77 8221 7000 | Email: tj.qureshi@oxcomm.com | Website: <a href="https://www.oxcomm.com">www.oxcomm.com</a> | 1 Dock Road, London, E16 1AH United Kingdom.

I hereby certify that the above information are certified true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Amzath Ali Mohamed Ansari